

SOFTWARE ENGINEER . BACKEND DEVELOPER

Baku, Azerbaijan

□ (+994) 51-641-60-17 | ■ akhundov1murad@gmail.com | □ https://github.com/akhundMurad | □ https://www.linkedin.com/in/akhundov1murad/

Summary

Software Engineer and Backend Development Instructor. Have experience with different types of architecture and technologies. Currently thoroughly learning Software Architecture and Data Engineering. Worked on Learning Management Systems, Internet Marketing Platforms, Smart Advertising Management Systems and so on. In addition to this, I train future specialists in the Backend Development. In my spare time I work on my Open Source projects. Ready for interesting and challenging tasks.

Experience _____

Devox Software Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar 2022 - Present

- · Worked on implementation of the Test Driven Development, that increased code quality and reduced production risks.
- Implemented Serverless Approach, using Azure Functions, to minimize infrastructure complexity and its costs.
- Organized Asynchronous Communication between several services via Azure Service Bus.
- · Refactored multiple services, according to the best practices, to decrease maintenance and scalability costs.
- · Reduced loading time of the main application by 65%, by optimization of MongoDB queries and applying caching strategies.
- · Implemented Analytical Calculations Service for advertising campaigns, with statistics from Instagram, Tiktok and Youtube.
- Improved CI/CD using Gitlab Pipelines and Docker, Docker Compose.

Tech Academy Baku, Azerbaijan

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT INSTRUCTOR

• Taught 10+ future specialists fundamental skills of the Backend Development.

Remote

Jun 2022 - Present

BACKEND DEVELOPER Feb. 2021 - Mar. 2022

- Applied the approach which helped to develop highly maintainable code.
- Used Celery and Redis to implement online meetings platform.
- Built API between Django REST Framework and BigBlueButton server.
- Optimized database access by applying tools and methods such as caching, stress testing (k6), decreasing queries number, correction of the database structure.
- Applied Sentry which contributed to find and fix 100+ issues.
- Used Docker and Docker Compose for deploying and development.
- Reviewed more then 100 pull requests and helped to make code of contributors more cleaner and testable.
- Taught 2 Junior Developers to best practices of software development

Self Employment Remote

Backend Developer Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Participated in startups and learned to work in a team.
- Used Django REST Framework to develop backend part of services.
- Applied best practices such as TDD, SOLID to achieve maintainable and testable code.

Skills_

OG

Python, FastAPI, Flask, Django, Django Rest Framework, Linux, Git, Github, Gitlab, Docker, Docker Compose, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, SocketIO, Nginx, SQL, Firebase, Azure Service Bus, Azure Blob Storage, Azure Functions, Google Cloud VMs, Google Cloud Storage, Celery, Concurrency and Parallelism, Websockets, TDD, REST Architecture, SOLID, OOP, Domain Driven Design, Microservices Architecture

Education

ASOIU(Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University)

Baku, Azerbaijan

B.S. IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES AND MANAGEMENT

Sep. 2020 - Sep. 2024

School of Ramin Mahmudzade

Baku, Azerbaijan

PROBLEM SOLVING

Sep. 2014 - Sep. 2015